# -Sara Coren - Web Developer

#### CONTACT

610.772.1279

sara.coren@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saracoren

https://github.com/saracoren

https://saracoren.github.io/ Portfolio2020

#### **SKILLS**

WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs, Mongo, Materialize, Bootstrap, Heroku, Ruby on Rails, SQL, React, GitHub, Photoshop, Adobe XD, Canva, Gulp, Sass

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate of Completion, Software Engineering General Assembly

Masters in General and Special Education (Gr. 1-6) Touro College

Masters in Geography and Environmental Science University College London

Bachelors in Geology with a Minor in Sociology The College of William & Mary

#### **INTERESTS**

UX Design, Innovation, Traveling, Hiking, Kayaking, Volunteering, Cross-Stitching

#### **PROFILE**

I am a product driven full stack web developer excited about expanding my knowledge base in the field. I have been a life-long learner and elementary educator as well as a researcher, geoscientist and humanitarian. I am passionate about using my web development skills and human centered approach in design to help people around the world access information to improve the quality of their lives.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **User Interface Engineering | Web Developer Intern**

January 2020 - June 2020

North Andover, Massachusetts

- Creating a Pattern and Style Library and updating code across all of our websites
- Code responsive HTML emails, write custom CSS, schedule email campaigns in Mailchimp for 40K+ subscribers and track the results of A/B testing
- Utilize WordPress, Statamic and ExpressionEngine CMSs to publish content
- Write extensive documentation in Notion for future interns to reference

## answerYES Consulting | Web Developer Intern

June 2019 - January 2020

Stamford, Connecticut

- Worked with a small team to redesign and redevelop a WordPress website for a non-profit organization helping underserved kids in the Bridgeport community
- Gained experience with information architecture, site mapping, writing a custom child theme, working with WP plugins, Photoshop, Adobe XD, and Dreamweaver

# Signature Brand Factory | Web Developer Intern

October 2019 - December 2019 Southington, Connecticut

- Customized code on several different WordPress websites for various clients using the Divi theme
- Used Photoshop to optimize photos for web development

# Rectory School | Grade 2 & 3 Lead Teacher

August 2017 - June 2018

Pomfret, Connecticut

- Instructed a mixed class of 2<sup>nd</sup> and 3<sup>rd</sup> grade students across all subject areas
- Wrote original curriculum and developed project based science lessons, activities and projects to help students connect their learning to the real world

### Windham Public Schools | Substitute Math Coach and STEM Teacher

August 2015 - June 2017

Windham, Connecticut

- Worked as a math coach serving students in Grades K-5 with instructional support and providing data collection
- Substitute taught in various STEM classrooms in grades pre-K to 8

# New York City Dept. of Education | Grade 4 Lead Teacher

August 2010 - June 2018

New York, New York

- Worked in a small coaching group for Literacy Coaches with Columbia Teachers College staff developers
- Served as president of the School Leadership Team and gave professional development presentations to staff